So then, the next thing we want do is pull the movies that were liked for any user ID.
下一步 我们将提取任何 user_id 喜欢过的电影
So, given a particular user ID,
给定特定的 user_id 后
just pull the movies that they liked.
提取该用户喜欢过的电影
So, before we pull the movies that they watched,
之前我们提取了用户看过的电影
and now we want to basically subset the movies that they
现在从看过的电影中提取
watched to only be the movies that those individuals liked.
用户喜欢的电影这一子集
The way that we could do this,
提取方法是...
and again, for a lot of these functions,
对于这些函数
there's probably multiple possible solutions.
可能有很多种实现方法
So, if we look at user items,
我们看看 user_items
let's look at the head of that,
看看标题部分
just going to get rid of this for now.
暂时删除这些代码
So, what we're going to do is we're going to say,
我们要做的是
from this user items, DataFrame,
从这个 user_items DataFrame 中提取数据
pull the cases where the user is equal to the user you give me,
其中用户等于你提供的用户
and that the rating is greater than some number.
并且评分大于某个数字
So, right now, I'm saying is seven,
我将下限设为 7 分
but if you don't rate higher than a seven,
如果评分不超过 7 分
I don't claim that to be a movie that you liked even if you saw it,
那么我不认为你喜欢这部电影 即使你看过
you didn't necessarily like it.
也不一定就喜欢它
So, I just want an array of the movies that not only did you watch,
我想要获取一个由你不仅看过
but that you also liked.
而且喜欢的电影组成的数组
So, one of the ways we can do that is to use the query method.
我们可以使用 query() 方法
We can pull where the user ID is equal to, and this is nice,
在这里输入 user_id =
there's an @ symbol where you can then pass in this variable.
这个 @ 符号比较方便 在这里传入这个变量
So, this is saying, if you give me a two here,
如果这里是 2
pass that to enter this part of the query.
那么在 query() 的这一部分传入这个 2
Where the rating, so again,
然后是 rating
this user ID is the column that comes from the user items, DataFrame,
这个 user_id 是 user_items DataFrame 中的列
and rating as another column that comes from that,
rating 是其中的另一列
and where that's greater than basically the min rating minus one.
大于 @min_rating - 1
You can also do this as like a greater than or equal to the min rating.
也可以设成大于等于 min_rating
From there, I'm just going to pull the movie IDs.
接着提取 movie_id
So, this'll subset to just this DataFrame,
从此 DataFrame 中
the movies that we care about,
提取我们关心的电影
and then I'm going to just pull the movie IDs.
提取这些 movie_id
I'll wrap that in a NumPy array too similar to the above.
将结果封装在 NumPy 数组中 和上面的相似
Again, we could try this out,
我们可以尝试一下这些代码
make sure that it works.
确保能运行
So, if we do movies liked by, let's say,
运行 movies_liked(2)
user two again, sorry,
抱歉
this should be a double equals.
这里应该是两个等号
One equal is assignment,
一个等号是赋值语句
double equals is an evaluation statement.
两个等号是评估语句
So, this is equal to two.
这里等于 2
So, where this is equal to two and this is greater than six,
这个大于 6
those are the movies that user two liked.
这些是用户 2 喜欢的电影
So that looks pretty good,
看起来一切正常
I'm going to make that fix down here as well.
下面的代码也更正下
Next, we want to just pull the movie names.
接下来我们将提取片名
So, what we've done so far is we found the users who are most similar,
到目前为止 我们已经找到最相似的用户
we have this function that pulls the movies that any individual likes,
这个函数能够提取任何用户喜欢的电影
and then what we want to do is take those movies that they liked based on the ID,
下面我们将根据 ID 获取他们喜欢的电影
and then pull the particular movies name,
并提取片名
and this maybe could be deemed as an unnecessary step,
这一步看起来没必要
but I think it's just simplifies the process.
但是我认为可以简化流程
So, if we go into the movies, DataFrame,
我们将从 movies DataFrame 中
and pull the movie ID,
提取 movie_id
and say, is in movie IDs.
输入 isin (movie_ids)
So, you can imagine this is an array or a list of some kind, and basically,
这个是一个数组或列表
if the movie ID is in there,
如果其中有该 movie_id
then what we want to do is pull that from the DataFrame and then pull them movie title.
我们将从 DataFrame 中提取该 ID 然后提取片名
So, this might seem a little confusing at this point,
看起来有点混乱
so let's go up, I'll show you what the movie is.
往上滚动 看看 movies 表格是什么样的
So, what we're saying is,
我们将
go in and look at this movie ID column.
查看这个 movie_id 列
If the list that you give me contains whatever ID I'm looking at,
如果你提供的列表包含我在查看的 ID
then pull this movie name out and give it back to me.
则提取并返回此片名
So, pull this movie name value back
对于在你提供的列表中的所有 movie_id
for any of these movie IDs that are in the list that you gave me.
提取并返回片名值
I'll do that as a list,
我将这部分设为列表
you could do this as a NumPy array if you want it to,
你也可以设为 NumPy 数组
it just says to do it as a list,
这里表示设为列表
so I'll follow the docstring.
我将它放在 ... 后面